Ross, when's this comet thing start?
羅斯，這個彗星的事 到底什麼時候開始？
Well, technically, it started 7 billion years ago.
理論上來說，七百萬年前
Okay. Fine, I'll stop. No teaching, okay?
好，我不講課，好嗎？
We'll just watch the pretty light streaking across the sky.
我們只欣賞美麗的流光劃過天空
Okay?
好嗎？
Whose official name is Bapstein-King. Okay! Okay!
它的正式名字 是巴布斯坦王，好！好！
There it is. Oh, look at that!
在那兒，你看！
Isn't Mother Nature amazing?
大自然真是神奇
That's a plane.
那是一台飛機
Well, all right, 1700 bags of peanuts flying that high...
好吧，1700袋的花生 飛在那麼高的地方…
that's pretty amazing too.
也是很神奇
-I wonder if you can see my apartment. -No, you can't.
-我在想能不能看到我家 -不能，看不到
-What? -I don't know.
-什麼？ -我不知道
Man, look at all those stars.
看看這些星星
Infinite space. It really makes you wonder, doesn't it?
無涯的天空，讓你有無盡遐思，是不？
-Know what else makes you wonder? -What?
-知道還有什麼讓你有無盡遐思？ -什麼？
Check out the rack on that chick.
看看那個妞的胸部
The One Where They're Up All Night
本集播出：六人行夜未眠
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
We've been out here for two hours...
我們已經在外面兩個小時了…
and we haven't seen any stupid comets. Can we go now?
還沒看到笨彗星，我們可以走了嗎？
I mean, Chandler's getting chilly.
我是說，錢德冷死了
No, I'm not.
不，我沒有
Then why are you wearing Monica's jacket?
那你為什麼穿著摩妮卡的夾克？
Because it's flattering!
因為好看！
Come on, Monica. Come on, Monica.
走吧，摩妮卡，走吧，摩妮卡
-We're going too. We got a movie. -I won't say no to a movie.
-我們也要走了，租了電影看 -我從不錯過看電影
Oh, Phoebe, we just actually wanted to be alone.
菲比，其實我們想獨處
-Sh. Get me out of here. -Oh, okay.
-帶我一起走 -哦，好
-Hey, Ross. -What?
-嘿，羅斯 -怎樣？
-Check it out. -Is it the comet?
-你看看 -那是彗星嗎？
No. Look, there's a bug stuck in tar right here.
不，那是只被焦油黏住的蟲
I can't believe..
我不能相信…
I bring you to see the Bapstein-King comet...
我帶你來看巴布斯坦王彗星…
one of nature's most spectacular phenomena...
大自然最壯觀的現象之一…
and all you care about are bugs stuck in tar and some woman.
而你只關心被焦油黏住的蟲 和一個女人
You know, there's two women, dude.
你知道，有兩個女人，老兄
Show me where.
在哪裡
Okay. Right up here.
好，在那裡
Joey, where's the pipe that was holding the door open?
喬伊，我們拿來頂住門的管子呢？
I don't know.
我不知道
Yeah, I do.
哦，我知道
-Joey! -What? Hey, don't look at me!
-喬伊！ -怎樣？嘿，別看著我！
You wanted to come up here and look for some stupid Burger King comet.
是你要上來看什麼笨漢堡王彗星的
It's called the Bapstein-King comet, okay?
它叫做巴布斯坦王彗星，好嗎？
Hey, Bapstein was a very well-respected astronomer from..
嘿，巴布斯坦是一位 很受尊敬的太空人，由…
No!
不！
-Monica. -She's sleeping.
-摩妮卡 -她在睡覺
I know. Just a quick question.
我知道，很快問一個問題
Which one was Deep Impact and which one was Armageddon?
那一部是《彗星撞地球》 那一部是《世界末日》？
Deep Impact was the one with Robert Duvall.
《彗星撞地球》是有勞勃杜瓦那部
Armageddon is what's going to happen to you if you wake me up.
《世界末日》是如果你叫醒我 會發生在你身上的
Sorry, I just can't sleep.
抱歉，我睡不著
Where's that book you're reading with two women who are ice-skating...
你在看的那本書在哪兒？ 有兩個女人在溜冰…
and wearing those hats with the flowers on it.
戴著有花的帽子的
Because every time I look at that cover, I'm like..
每次我一看到它的封面，我就…
It's in the living room,  where there's also a light...
在客廳，那兒有燈…
and no one will kick you in the shin.
而且沒有人會踢你小腿
What?
什麼？
Please don't be a spaceship. Please don't be a spaceship.
拜託不要是太空船 拜託不要是太空船
Oh, thank God.
感謝上帝
How could you be beeping? I just disconnected you!
你怎麼可能還在？我把你斷電了！
I took out your battery! How can..? Don't interrupt me!
我拿掉了你的電池！ 怎麼還能…？不要打斷我說話！
Monica! Monica!
瑞秋！摩妮卡！
Come on!
真是的！
I can't believe this!
真受不了！
All right, well, I guess we know what we have to do to get down.
好吧，我想我們知道 要怎麼做才能下去
Yeah, I guess we don't have a choice.
是啊，我想我們沒有選擇
Help us! Please, help us!
救命！救救我們！
We're stuck up on the roof, and we can't get down!
我們被困在屋頂，下不去！
Ross.
羅斯
I was thinking we'd just go down the fire escape.
我是在想用逃生梯下去
I know. I wasn't finished.
我知道，我還沒說完
But don't worry!
但是不用擔心！
We're gonna go down the fire escape!
我們會用逃生梯下去！
Sh!
I'm sorry, I thought I'd make some warm milk and it would help me sleep.
抱歉，我想熱點牛奶來幫助睡眠
With a wok?
用炒菜鍋？
My boring book didn't put you to sleep?
我以為你要看我的書來幫助睡覺？
It got interesting.
它後來變得很有意思
Damn you, Oprah!
可惡的歐普拉！
Here, let me make the milk. I'm up anyway.
這兒，我來替你熱牛奶 反正我已經起來了
You know what we could do now that we're up?
既然我們已經起來了 你知道可以做什麼嗎？
We could just talk to each other all night long.
我們可以促膝長談
Like when we were first dating. It'd be fun.
像我們剛開始約會時那樣 會很好玩的
-Okay, that does sound fun. -Yeah.
-好，聽來是很有意思 -是啊
So how bummed were you when the second sister died, huh?
第二個妹妹死的時候 你是不是很生氣？
The second sister dies?!
第二個妹妹死了？！
No.
沒有
No, I was talking about the book I was reading.
沒有，我是在說我在看的那本書
The second sister dies in Archie and Jughead Double Digest?
《阿契漫劃合集》裡第二個妹妹死了？
That's correct.
對
Want to go in the bedroom? It's more comfortable.
要不要進臥房去？比較舒服一點
-Sure. -Okay.
-當然 -好
Oh, wait, did you send those contracts to Milan?
等一下，你有沒有把合約寄去米蘭？
If this is your idea of sexy talk...
你覺得這是性感的談話…
Did you overnight the contracts I gave you?
你有沒有快遞寄出我拿給你的合約？
What contracts?
什麼合約？
Please tell me this is just one of your jokes that I don't get.
拜託，告訴我這是 你另一個我搞不懂的笑話
Like what?
像什麼？
Like the thing when you put the phone in your pants?
像是你把電話放在褲襠？
Tag, I'm serious. This isn't funny.
泰格，我很認真，這不好笑
Those contracts had to go out today.
那些合約今天一定要寄出去
You didn't give me any contracts.
你沒給我什麼合約
Yes, I did. I put a little Post-it on it that said:
有，我有，我還貼了 一張隨手貼，寫著：
"Must go out today, " and I underlined "today" three times.
「今天一定要寄出」 在「今天」下面劃了三道
Then I put a little heart in the corner so I wouldn't seem too bossy.
然後我還在角落劃了一顆心 因為我不想太像上司
You never gave them to me.
你沒有給我
If we went to the office, you would see those contracts sitting on your desk.
如果我們到辦公室去 你會看到它在你的辦公桌上
No, I'd see you looking embarrassed because they are not on my desk.
不，我會看到你很窘 因為它不在我的辦公桌上
Maybe I'm embarrassed because you talk on the phone with your crotch.
也許我很窘，是因為你用褲襠接電話
You want to go to the office now?
你要現在去辦公室？
Come on, it's late. We're not going down to the office.
算了，很晚了，我們不要到辦公室去
Yeah, I understand. I wouldn't want to be proved wrong either.
是，我瞭解，我也不會想 被證明是錯的
All right, get your coat!
好，拿外套！
Oh! When did you unhook this? Nice work!
你什麼時候解開的？好厲害！
It won't go down any further. It's stuck.
不能再下去了，卡住了
We'll just have to jump.
我們只有跳下去
Now, we're gonna have to make sure to land...
我們一定要確定著陸在…
to the right of that patch of ice, okay?
那塊冰的右邊，好嗎？
Not hit the dumpster on the other side.
不要撞到旁邊的垃圾桶
And try to avoid that weird brownish-red stuff in the middle.
試著避開中間那棕紅色的奇怪東西
So when you get down there...
當你下到下面以後…
you go up to the roof and you let me in.
你到屋頂讓我進去
-Wait a minute. I have to do it? -You'll be fine.
-等一下，要我去？ -你會沒事的
It'll be just like bungee jumping, you know?
就像高空彈跳
But instead of bouncing back up,  you won't.
但你不會回彈
Well, what if I smack my head on the concrete?
要是我的頭撞到水泥呢？
Well, I'm not gonna lie to you, Joey. It's a possibility.
喬伊，我不想騙你，是有這個可能的
I don't know. Tell you what,  let's flip to see who does it.
我不知道，這樣吧，擲銅板決定誰去
-You call it in the air, all right? -Oh, all right.
-在空中時說出你要的那一面，好吧？ -好吧
-Can you see what it is? -No.
-你看得到是那一面嗎？ -不行
-Okay. Well, you be careful. -No, Ross, stop it.
-你小心一點 -羅斯，不要這樣
I'm not jumping.
我不跳
Look, I have an audition tomorrow, and I can't go if I break my leg.
明天我要試鏡 如果摔斷腿就不能去了
Well, I'm not jumping. I have a son. He won't have a father if I die.
我不跳，我有一個兒子 要是我死了他就沒爸爸了
So it looks like we're even.
看來我們平手
Okay, so this wire...
好，這條線…
is connected to this wire, which plugs into here.
接到這條線，插到這兒
Okay, so to get the beeping to stop, all I have to do...
好，讓嗶聲停止，我只要…
Okay.
Well done, Phoebe.
做得好，菲比
What do you want from me?!
你要我怎麼樣？！
Here's your milk. What should we talk about?
你的牛奶來了，你想談什麼？
What? What? What?
什麼？什麼？什麼？
Oh, were you sleeping, sweetie? I'm sorry. Here.
甜心，你在睡覺嗎？抱歉，這兒
Okay. Feel free to look...
好，你愛怎麼找都行…
but I'm telling you those contracts are not here.
不過我告訴你 那些合約沒在這張桌上
How could you know? Look at this mess, Tag.
你怎麼可能知道？ 你看看有多亂，泰格
This is what I'm saying. You have to be more organized.
這就是我說的，你一定要有組織一點
You've got newspapers, you've got magazines, you.. Oh!
有報紙，有雜誌，你…喔！
And who's this chippy?
這小妞是誰？
A little young for you, but whatever.
對你來說太幼齒一點，隨便啦
That's my sister.
是我妹
Really? Very cute braces.
真的？牙套好可愛
Anyway, you know what? The point is, Tag, start looking...
你知道嗎？重點是 泰格，開始找吧…
because you're gonna find those contracts on your desk.
你會在你桌上找到那些合約
So when do you imagine you gave them to me? Morning or afternoon?
你想像是什麼時候給我的？ 早上還是下午？
In the afternoon. Mr. Zelner came into my office after lunch...
下午，顏先生午餐後 進來我辦公室…
he put them on my desk,  and then I put a Post-it on it...
他把它放在我桌上 我貼了一張隨手貼在上面…
that said:
寫著：
"Must go out today."
「今天一定要寄出」
So you just keep looking in there, all right?
請你繼續找，好嗎？
They're not here.
不在這裡
Puzzler.
奇怪奇怪
Bit of a puzzle.
真奇怪
Why don't you check the copy room? Maybe the contracts are in there.
你去影印室找一找，也許你放在那兒
-How could I have left them there? -I don't know.
-我怎麼可能放在那兒？ -我不知道
How can your genitals make phone calls?
你的私處怎麼可能打電話？
Okay? It's not a perfect world. Just go, please?
好嗎？這不是個完美的世界 請你去找一找
-Fine. -Thank you.
-好吧 -謝謝
Hello?
喂？
I still don't get it.
我還是不懂
You still awake?
你還醒著嗎？
Yeah. You?
是啊，你呢？
You do know that was me that just said that, right?
你知道說話的是我吧？
Hey.
嘿
As long as we're both up...
既然我們都醒著…
Yeah?
怎樣？
I hope you're not thinking about cleaning the living room.
我希望你不是想要打掃客廳
Man, I'm starving. What the hell was I thinking at dinner?
我餓死了，晚飯時我在想什麼啊？
"Do you want soup or salad?" Both, always order both.
「你要湯還是沙拉？」 兩樣都要，永遠都兩樣都要
You know, I'm looking,  and I don't think anyone's home here.
我看了半天，我想沒人在家
I say we just break the window...
我說我們打破窗戶…
crawl through...
爬進去…
and you know, explain later.
之後再解釋
-No one's home? -I don't think so.
-沒人在家？ -我想沒有
Hello?
喂？
So when you get in there...
當你進去之後…
Okay. This is where you and I part ways.
你我該在這裡分手了
Noisy bitch!
吵死人的賤貨！
Oh, what? What are you doing?
怎麼？你在幹什麼？
Do you know what just happened?
你知道剛剛發生什麼事嗎？
Yeah. We had sex and then we fell asleep.
是啊，我們做愛，然後睡著了
No. We were in the middle of sex...
不，我們做了一半…
and you fell asleep.
然後你睡著了
No. No, that's not true.
不，不，沒有這回事
No, best time ever.
不，這是最棒的一次
Yeah. You rock my world.
你震撼了我的世界
-Monica? -What?
-摩妮卡？ -怎麼？
I was giving you some of my best moves, and you missed it.
這是我表現最好的時候，你錯過了
So please wake up so we can do it right.
請你醒來，好好做完它
Okay. Okay. I'm ready.
好，好，我準備好了
-Come on, big fella. -Okay.
-來，大哥 -好
-Give me the good stuff. -Yeah.
-好好表現一番 -是啊
No, no, no. Don't fall asleep.
不，不，不，不要睡覺
Okay, I'm going to make you some coffee.
我要替你煮咖啡
Well, I probably won't spill coffee grounds all over the kitchen floor.
我大概不會把咖啡粉灑了一地
Okay, I'm up. I'm up.
好吧，我起來了，我起來了
Hi. I got you some coffee to..
嘿，咖啡來了…
So you got anything for me?
你找到東西了沒？
-Still no luck. -Oh, my God.
-還是沒有 -我的天
You checked your entire desk and all the drawers?
你有檢查過整個桌子 和所有的抽屜嗎？
-Want me to check again? -I wish you would.
-要我再找一次？ -請你再找一次
Well, no, it's not in there.
它沒有在這裡
How about that drawer?
那個抽屜呢？
Well, it's not out here. Any chance it could be in your office?
它不在這裡，有可能在你辦公室嗎？
I don't know.
我不知道
I mean, let me check.
我找找看
Any luck?
有嗎？
See you in my office for a minute?
請進來說話
You found them!
你找到了！
I'm not even gonna gloat.
我不會偷笑
-I'm just really relieved it's.. -You put these on my desk.
-我很安慰整件事… -你放在我桌上的
-I did not. -Oh, really?
-我沒有 -真的嗎？
So they left your bottom drawer...
它從你最下面的抽屜溜出來…
crawled across the floor, then jumped onto my desk?
爬過地板，跳到我桌上來？
How did you know they were in my bottom drawer?
你怎麼知道它在我最下面的抽屜？
I am so hot for you right now.
此刻你令我慾火焚身
Oh, my God! How did you get back here?
我的天！你怎麼回來的？
Phoebe Buffay?
菲比布非？
Fire Alarm?
警報器？
Oh, hi, Officer Fireman. Can I help you?
嗨，救火員先生，有什麼事嗎？
Your fire alarm was in the trash.
我們在垃圾桶發現你的警報器
-That's not mine. -Yes, it is.
-不是我的 -是你的
How do you know?
你怎麼知道？
If you dump a fire alarm, don't use a blanket that says:
下次你丟掉警報器時 不要用寫著
"Property of Phoebe Buffay, not Monica."
「菲比布非財物 不是摩妮卡的」的毯子
Do you have a search warrant?
你有搜索令嗎？
Because the last time I checked, this was still America.
我查過了，這裡還是美國
Please reattach it. It's illegal to disconnect them.
請把它裝回去，拆除它是違法的
Fine. But please, God, tell me how to stop it from going off?
好吧，拜託告訴我 怎樣才能讓它不叫？
Press the reset button.
壓下重設的按鈕
There's a reset button? Oh, thank you. Thank you.
有重設按鈕？謝謝，謝謝
Oh. There's a reset button?
有重設按鈕？
My God!
我的天！
Why didn't I see that?
我怎麼沒看到？
Reset button. Reset button.
重設按鈕，重設按鈕
Where is there a reset button? Oh, here it is! Oh!
重設按鈕在哪裡？ 哦，在這兒！喔！
-Okay, you have a good grip? -Yeah.
-你抓好了嗎？ -好了
I'm gonna start to climb down you now.
我要開始爬過你了
-All right, just hurry up. -Okay.
-好，快一點 -好
Now, should I climb down your front so we're face to face...
我應該面向你爬下來 所以我們面對面的…
or should I climb down your back so we're...
還是應該背對你爬下來…
butt to face?
然後屁股對著臉？
-Face to face. -I like face to face.
-面對面 -我喜歡面對面
-Okay, here I come. -All right.
-我來了 -好
Oh, my.. How much do you weigh, Ross?
我的天…羅斯，你多重？
I prefer not to answer. I'm still carrying a little holiday weight.
我不想回答，過節時胖的還沒瘦下去
When we talked about face to face...
我們說要面對面時…
I don't think we thought it all the way through.
我想我們沒有想清楚
-What do you want me to do? -Just shimmy down me and drop.
-你要我怎麼辦？ -從我身上滑下，跳下去
-Hi. -Hi.
-嘿 -嘿
You know, maybe I should hang,  and you should climb down me.
也許我該吊著，你爬過我下去
Yeah? Maybe we should talk about that for a little while!
是嗎？也許我們應該多討論一下！
-It still looks pretty far. -It's not that far. Just drop.
-看起來還好遠 -沒有那麼遠，跳就是了
Do not rush me!
不要催我！
My pants are starting to come down, and I'm not wearing any underwear.
我的褲子開始下滑，我沒穿內褲
My ankle! I really hurt my ankle!
我的腳踝！我傷到我的腳踝！
I think I twisted it when.. A quarter!
我想我扭到了…二十五分！
That really was some of your best work.
真的是你的最佳表現
I told you.
我說了嘛
I can't believe it.
真不能相信
I've only got two hours until I call in sick for work.
只剩兩小時我就要打電話請假
I have to be up in seven minutes.
我7分鐘後就要起床
Well, you're not gonna believe this, but if you have seven minutes...
你不會相信的，如果你還有7分鐘…
Really?
真的？
You want to?
你想要？
You get the vacuum cleaner. I'll get the furniture polish.
你去拿吸塵器，我拿傢俱打亮劑